Guide to the Mary Hunter Wolf Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- June 1996 Acquisition, 1867-1996; 1; 46.26 linear feet (69 boxes)
  - Audiocassettes, [circa 1979-1988]
    - Clemente GIT interviews, 1980 April 15-17; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367725)
    - Crashow - Ridgefield, 1988 April 13; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367733)
    - [Kaplan?] - Wed., undated; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367741)
    - Wolf 1 / Wolf 2, 1987 November 11; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367758)
    - D/T Arts Pilot, Ginny Bales, History of Pop, Music I, Wolcott Tech, 1985 November 29; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367766)
    - D/T Arts Pilot, Wolcott Tech, Bob Eberle - Acoustics, 1985 November 5; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367774)
    - [Mary Hunter Wolf] tells AM, Chapel Hill, 1981 June 22; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367782)
    - Physical Skills of the Actor - Rob Rhys, Dale Place, Kaynor Tech, Waterbury, 1978 October 19; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367790)
    - D/T Arts Pilot, Tom Devino-percussion, Andress Jannson-woodwinds and acoustics, 1985 November 25; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367808)
    - Wesleyan U., AM and afternoon, undated; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367816)
    - Paul [Torvreull?]...IRVS intro...move like Houston, undated; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367824)
    - Shakespeare + All That Jazz, Cleo Laine - John Dankworth / Shakespeare + All That Jazz conclusion, Cleo Laine live at Carnegie Hall, undated; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367832)
    - CTTE Board Meeting, 1983 February 4; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367840)
    - Board CTTE (side 3), undated; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367857)
    - Art Studies, 1979 August 14; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367865)
    - [?] workshops and CTTE, undated; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367873)
    - J. Lobell, undated; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367881)
    - Rollo May - Creativity Lecture #1, undated; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367899)
    - Rollo May - Creativity Lecture #2, undated; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367907)
    - "William Shakespeare: A Portrait in Sound", NPR, undated; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367915)
      stereo
    - Conversations with Will - 38:30, undated; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367923)
    - Mary Hunter Wolf #9, 1988 February 15; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367931)
    - Mary Hunter Wolf #9 (side 3) / Mary Hunter Wolf #10 (side 1), 1988 February 15-25; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367964)
    - Mary Wolf: 3rd Session, Wellesley - Santa Fe, 1987 December 17; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367949)
    - Mary Wolf: 4th Session, Chicago, 1988 January 7; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367956)
    - One of these Humanities Workshop over Polio [?], undated; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367972)
    - Mary Wolf #14, 1988 May 17; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367980)
    - Mary Wolf #12, 1988 April 20; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099367998)
    - Mary Hunter Wolf #13, 1988 May 13; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099368004)
    - Mary Hunter Wof and Crystal Brian, 1991 September 16; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099368012)
    - Mary Wolf #10 (sides 2 and 3), 1988 February 25; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099368020)
    - Renzuli et [?] / Renzuli (stops at Torrington), 1979 July 10; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099368038)
    - Gifted & Talented Workshop tapes, undated; 1 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002099368046)
    - CTTE, 1982 October; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368749)
      This audiocassette includes written notes.
    - Romeo & Juliet, Washington I + II, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368756)
    - "Music Mountain", Manhatten String Quartet, Mozart Quartet K. 525, Prokofiev Ov. on Jewish Themes, MSQ..., 1983 June 25; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368764)
    - Leo [?], undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368772)
    - K[?] contel to [?], undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368780)
    - Scott etc. [?], 1981[?]; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368798)
    - AST [?] WTIC, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368806)
    - Clemente G/T interviews, 1980 April 15-17; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368814)
    - Chapel Hill [Pato?] class, 1981 June 22; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368822)
    - Rollo May, Creativity, Lecture #3, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368830)
    - Rollo May, Creativity, Lecture #4, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368848)
    - Title III interview of three students (ECA, New Haven), 1976 November 17; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368855)
    - Update [?], 1981 May 7; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368863)
    - Mary Wolf #11, 1988 April 8-12; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368871)
    - Feels aft. Co[?] Resouvres, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368889)
    - [?] LTI mixed, Friday read [?], undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368897)
    - Pal[?] [?] Wed / Shady Kaplan continued, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368905)
    - Drama Tech, 2nd hour, Coordinators Meeting, 1980 June 4; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368913)
    - Menpla[?] Tem. A.M., Stein Ratteson, Tape I, 1981 March 19; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368921)
    - Menpla[?], Tape II, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368939)
    - Menpla[?], Tape III, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368947)
    - Update, teatro Wolf, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368954)
    - Inter Arts, Atlanta, 1977 April 13; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368962)
    - Sandy Rieshot on crisis in identifying gifted [material?], undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368970)
    - Teen Life Conference-2 Reports, 1991 March 6; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368988)
    - Drama Tech, 1st hour, coordinators meeting includes discussion of MacBeth, Wilcox Tech, 1980 June 4; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099368996)
    - Wolf [?], 1987 November 20-28; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099369002)
    - Who is the Gifted Child?, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099369010)
    - #2 Update g/t, 1981 May 6; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099369028)
    - "Looking at Korean Culture Through Its Art", Hesung Koh etal (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1987 July 6; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099369036)
      The curriculum panel includes Mary Hunter Wolf.
    - "Looking at Korean Culture", "Korean Life Cycle", Hesung Koh etal (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1987 July 6; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099369044)
    - Kenneth Champlin, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099369051)
    - Poor tape til ?, 3 spot of A, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099369069)
    - Mary Wolf - session 5, 1988 January 13; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099369077)
    - Mary Wolf - 6th session, 1988 January 21; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099369085)
    - Mary Wolf - 7th session, 1988 January 29; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099369093)
    - Mary Hunter Wolf - 8th session, 1988 February 5; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002099369101)
  - Audiocassettes, [circa 1991-1994]
    Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Mary Hunter Wolf and Crystal Brian, 1991 September 16; 1 (Box 81, Item barcode 39002099368707)
    - Books sold in New Haven, undated; 1 (Box 81, Item barcode 39002099368715)
    - Tamara Day [?], Memorial Gathering of Friends (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1980 December 6; 1 (Box 81, Item barcode 39002099368723)
    - Tamara Day [?], Memorial Gathering of Friends (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1980 December 6; 1 (Box 81, Item barcode 39002099368731)
  - American Shakespeare Festival Theatre book, music; clippings; New York Times Magazine, [circa 1918-1985]; 8 (Box 65)
    Includes 1918--Peace; Los Angeles papers.
  - Musical scores, old scripts 1930s; printed material and clippings, 1974, undated; 6 (Box 66)
  - Printed material, musical scores; photographs, circa 1940-1966; 4 (Box 67)
  - The Respectful Prostitute, photographs, watercolors, undated; 5 (Box 68)
  - Scrapbook, posters, undated; 2 (Box 69 (Oversize))
- March 1997 Acquisition, 1950-1996; 2; 0.42; (1 box)
  This acquisition includes printed material, including theatre production programs, material related to the Yale-New Haven Teachers Institute, photographs from the Dallas Starlight Operetta production of Annie Get Your Gun, and other productions, and "Production Script of Ballet Ballads ."
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Letters of James Hunter, photocopies, [1994] (Box 70)
  - Ballet Ballads, script, undated (Box 70)
  - Celebration by Horton Foote, photocopy, [1996] (Box 70)
  - Unsorted photographs, 1950, undated; 2 (Box 70)
  - Printed material, 1975-1995; 7 (Box 70)
- December 1997 Acquisition, 1921-1995; 3; 0.92 linear feet (3 boxes) + 1 broadside
  This acquisition includes printed material, ephemera, and a scrapbook labeled "To Mary Hunter Wolf. On the Occasion of her Move to Anchorage, Alaska" containing letters and photographs.
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 546.
  - Printed material and production programs, circa 1921-1923 (Box 71)
  - Empty box labeled "J.M. Hunter letters", undated (Box 71)
  - Letter from Lucy, undated (Box 71)
  - Prince William Sound Community College, Fourth Annual Theatre Conference (2 copies), 1996 (Box 71)
  - Prince William Sound Community College Award, 1995 August 19 (Box 71)
  - Scrapbook, undated (Box 72)
  - Carib Song set design drawings, 1945 (Box 73 (Broadside))
  - Diploma from Columbia University for Mary H. Wolf's Bachelor of Science degree, 1945 June 5 (Box 74)
    Includes printed commencement address.
- February 1999 Acquisition, 1939-1998; 4; 1.63 linear feet (3 boxes)
  This acquisition includes correspondence, writings, photographs, audiotapes, printed material, and ephemera.
  Box 77 (reel-to-reel tape): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 614.
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1939-1997, undated; 3 (Box 75)
  - Correspondence, photographs, and printed material, 1946-1992, undated; 2 (Box 75)
  - The Sagacity and Intelligence of the Horse, undated (Box 75)
  - Address book and correspondence, 1955, undated (Box 75)
  - Appointment calendars, 1997-1998; 2 (Box 75)
  - Society of Stage Directors and Choreographers, 1996-1998 (Box 75)
    Includes bylaws, balance sheets, and board meeting agendas.
  - Lecture notes and typescript essay by A. S. Moffett about Arthur Miller from the Fourth Annual Prince William Sound Community College Theatre Conference, 1996 (Box 75)
  - Printed material and newspaper clippings, 1994-1998; 7 (Box 75)
  - Family photographs, 1959-1996, undated (Box 75)
  - Mary Hunter Wolf Dissertation, pages 181-224 (1 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002099368590)
    Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Mary Hunter Wolf Dissertation, pages 225-289 (2 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002099368608)
  - Newsweek Commemorative Issue: Diana (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1997; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002099368657)
    Contents focus on Princess Diana of Wales.
    Manufactured by American Printing House for the Blind.
  - Newsweek (2 of 6 audiocassettes), 1998 January 26; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002099368665)
    Contents include allegations, leaks, gossip....Clinton's sex life.
  - Newsweek (3 of 6 audiocassettes), 1998 February 9; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002099368624)
    Contents include Stewart and Michum death, suicide....Cunanan.
    Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access services for further information.
  - Newsweek (5 of 6 audiocassettes), 1998 July 6; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002099368632)
    Contents include Clinton.
  - Newsweek (6 of 6 audiocassettes), 1998 August 17; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002099368640)
    Contents include: campaign reform and bombing in Kenya and Tanzania.
  - Newsweek (4 of 6 audiocassettes), 1998 April 6; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002099368616)
    Contents include children murders, Clinton trip to Africa, Russia...Vietnam.
  - Peter Pan (audiotape reel), 1960 December 8; 1 (Box 76, Item barcode 39002099368673)
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Cosmetic powder case with mirror, undated (Box 77)
  - Small metal box, undated (Box 77)
  - Empty envelope, 1998 November 9 (Box 77)
  - Tomato slicer, kitchen utensil in box, undated (Box 77)
- March 1999 Acquisition, 1890-1998; 5; 1.67 linear feet (3 boxes)
  This acquisition includes correspondence, writings, printed material, and photographs.
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 607.
  - Unsorted photographs and slides, 1890-1997, undated; 7 (Box 78)
  - Printed material, 1974-1993; 2 (Box 78)
  - "Mary Hunter Wolf: Director, Producer, Educator, Building Communities Through Theatre," dissertation by Tamara L. Compton, 1992 (Box 78)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1998, undated; 2 (Box 78)
  - Notes, printed material, 1998, undated (Box 78)
  - Center for Theatre Techniques in Education, 1971-1997 (Box 78)
    Includes newspaper clippings, printed material, and typescript presentation on Andrius Jilinsky by MHW.
  - Writings, photographs and other materials relating to a biography of MHW, 1944-1998, undated; 6 (Box 79)
  - Correspondence of Mary Austin, photocopies, 1919, undated (Box 80 (Oversize))
  - Guggenheim Magazine, 1993 (Box 80 (Oversize))
- December 2000 Acquisition, undated; 6; 0.21 linear feet (1 box)
  Purchased from Jerry Haendiges Productions on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 2012.
  General
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 88.
  Box 81 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - The Easy Aces radio show, episodes 1-4 (1 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 81, Item barcode 39002099368681)
    Mary Hunter Wolf played the role of "Marge".
  - The Easy Aces radio show, episodes 5-8 (2 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 81, Item barcode 39002099368699)